Abin Baby Web Application Developer

2314, rue Parthenais, Montreal QC, H2K 3T5

+1(514)-974-3529

abinbabymenachery@gmail.com

in <u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

Α¤

English, Malayalam, Hindi, Basic French

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages:

JavaScript, MySQL, jQuery, PHP, Java, C#, Python, C, C++.

Frameworks:

MERN, MEAN, Apache, ASP.NET Core, Bootstrap, Laravel 8

IDE:

VS Code, Eclipse, Visual Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, MATLAB, Anaconda, SSMS

Design Patterns:

MVC, Singleton, observer design, IIFE

Databases:

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MSSQL, MongoDB

Operating system:

Windows (7/8/10), Linux, kali, Tails

Services:

Docker, Mail-SMTP, IIS, Apache

Version-control system:

Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, TFS

Project management tools:

Trello, Asana

PROFILE

Hard-working and enthusiastic professional with more than 2 years of experience and a reliable knowledge of application development, web platform development, and content design using **React**, **Node.JS**, **HTML 5**, **CSS 3**. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the full-stack web developer role at your company.

EXPERIENCE

WEB APPLICATION DEVLOPER (INTERN)

Intuitive Web System, Bangalore, India

2019 - 2019

- > Design, build, or maintain web Applications
- Collect user Feedback
- > Perform direct web content changes
- Manage database content.
- > Run sample project in different systems.
- Write reports on meetings.
- > Reply to the emails from customer.

NETWORK TECHNICIAN / SUPPORT SPECIALIST

Asianet Broadband (Full time), Kochi- India

2018 - 2019

- Configuration and Installation of modem, routers and other network devices for internal networks.
- Answer incoming phone calls and provide support to callers' experiencing computer problems of all kinds. Listen to descriptions of customer issues and determine how and if they can be fixed.
- Troubleshoots by using the information from customers to diagnose tech issues and walk customers through the steps needed to fix various problems.
- Submit Service Requests, If customer tech problems cannot be handled over the phone, technical support representatives schedule a repair crew to fix problems on-site.
- Check for customer problems and fixes in the solutions database, and add new information to the database when and if new problems and fixes arise.
- Keep logs of all calls answered and addressed, including dates and times.
- Respond to emails and online chat requests for technical support.

PROJECTS

My Portfolio - | HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (Dec 2020)

• Employers can see my basic information and project works which I have done for my courses as well.

Link: My portfolio

Tesla Clone - | MERN, HTML5, CSS3

(Jan 2021)

- A cloned dynamic tesla website using MERN framework.
- I worked alone as a hobby project idea I found online.

Link: Tesla Clone Webapp

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Pizza chef 2019 Present

Pizza Hut, Montreal, QC

- Assure quality and cleanliness of the food.
- Ensure freshness of food and ingredients.
- Pay attention to detail when sending out a food item.

Uber Delivery Partner 2020 Present *Uber Technologies Inc*

 Pickup and delivering foods from various restaurants to

the customers.

 Pickup and drop-off passenger customers at their locations.

REFERENCES ARE AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST

Whatsapp Clone - | MERN, HTML5, CSS3

(Jan 2021)

- A cloned dynamic whatsapp webapp using MERN framework.
- I worked alone as a hobby project idea I found online.

Link: Whatsapp Clone Webapp

Countdown Timer - | HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (Oct 2020)

- A simple countdown timer for the next new year eve.
- Hobby Project.

Link: Countdown-timer

Memory Game - | HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (Oct 2020)

- A simple puzzle game created when I started learning JavaScript.
- Hobby Project.

Link: Memory Game

<u>Loan Prediction - | Python, Anaconda, Pandas</u> (Mar 2020)

- According to the input data the prediction will be produced if they are met the criteria.
- I worked alone as a hobby project idea I found online.

Link: Loan Prediction

<u>To-Do list App - | PHP, HTML5, CSS3, MySQL</u> (Feb 2020)

- Users can create to-do list for their daily routine.
- I worked on both front-end and back-end in a group of two people.

Link: To-do List

Hangman Game - | C++

(Dec 2019)

- Users can play hangman game in console.
- I worked in a group of two people.

Link: Hangman Game

Car Rental Services - | HTML5, CSS3

(Nov 2019)

(2019-present)

- A static website where, users can select their traveling companion from the given choices and book them for taking rent.
- I worked alone as a part of HTML and CSS Course.

Link: Car Rental Service App

Auto Reminder - | HTML5, CSS3, PHP, MySQL (Jan 2018)

- Users can get notifications as text messages and emails before their vehicles' each renewal dates.
- I worked on both front-end and back-end in a group of two people

EDUCATION

> AEC in Programming, Networks And Security

Institut Supérieur D'informatique ISI, Montreal,QC

Bachelors in Computer Aplication

Calicut University Of India - NIMIT, Kerala, India (2015 – 2018)